<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="way_cooler_keybindings_unstable_v1">
  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2019 Preston Carpenter

    Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute, and sell this
    software and its documentation for any purpose is hereby granted
    without fee, provided that the above copyright notice appear in
    all copies and that both that copyright notice and this permission
    notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name of
    the copyright holders not be used in advertising or publicity
    pertaining to distribution of the software without specific,
    written prior permission.  The copyright holders make no
    representations about the suitability of this software for any
    purpose.  It is provided "as is" without express or implied
    warranty.

    THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THIS
    SOFTWARE, INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND
    FITNESS, IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY
    SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES
    WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN
    AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION,
    ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF
    THIS SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>
  <interface name="zway_cooler_keybindings" version="1">
    <description summary="exclusively capture keys from other clients">
      This interface allows clients to register a list of keys that will never
      be sent to other clients.

      When these keys are part of keyboard events the relevant event will
      instead be sent to the client that bounds to this interface.
      
      This is intended for general keybindings, not for lock screens or other
      clients that already have surfaces to accept input for.
    </description>

    <enum name="key_state">
      <description summary="physical key state">
	Describes the physical state of a key that produced the key event.
      </description>
      <entry name="released" value="0" summary="key is not pressed"/>
      <entry name="pressed" value="1" summary="key is pressed"/>
    </enum>

    <request name="register_key">
      <description summary="register a key for capturing"/>
      <arg name="key" type="uint" summary="key to capture"/>
      <arg name="modifiers" type="uint" summary="A bit field describing modifiers"/>
    </request>

    <request name="clear_keys">
      <description summary="Clear all registered keys from capturing"/>
    </request>

    <event name="key">
      <description summary="key event">
	A key was pressed or released.
	The time argument is a timestamp with millisecond
	granularity, with an undefined base.
      </description>
      <arg name="time" type="uint" summary="timestamp with millisecond granularity"/>
      <arg name="key" type="uint" summary="key that produced the event"/>
      <arg name="state" type="uint" enum="key_state" summary="physical state of the key"/>
      <arg name="mods" type="uint" summary="depressed, latched, or locked modifiers"/>
    </event>

  </interface>
</protocol>
